{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "In Which year India get its Independence from the BritishRule",
      "options": ["1956", "1947", "1958", "1919"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "When did India came under the direct rule of the British crown?",
      "options": ["1757", "1764", "1858", "1930"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who will raise the flag during national level Independence day function in 2023 at Red Fort?",
      "options": [
        "Narendra Modi",
        "Pranab Mukherjee",
        "Ram Nath Kovind",
        "Rajnath Singh"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "'Tum mujhe khoon do, mein tumhe azadi doonga' was said by which of the following persons?",
      "options": [
        " Bhagat Singh",
        " Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "Subhash Chandra Bose",
        "Vallabhbhai Patel"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "East India Company started trade with India from which city?",
      "options": [
        "Bombay(Mumbai)",
        "Surat",
        "Madras (Chennai)",
        "Calcutta (Kolkata)"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the name of the mission sent by british government to India to seek cooperation during World War II?",
      "options": [
        "Cripps Mission",
        " Simon Commission",
        "United Kingdom Cabinet Mission",
        "Morley-Minto Mission"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following revolutionaries died due to hunger strike at Lahore jail?",
      "options": [
        "Kishori Lal",
        "Jatin Das",
        " Lala Lajpat Rai",
        "Madan Lal Dhingra"
      ],

      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following leaders is known as the 'Iron Man of India' ?",
      "options": [
        " Baldev Singh",
        "Bhagat Singh",
        "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
        "Vallabhbhai Patel"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "After independence, who was the first Governor-General of India?",
      "options": [
        "Rajendra Prasad",
        "Lord Mountbatten",
        "Lord Dalhousie",
        "C. Rajagopalachari"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "When did Vasco da Gama discovered the sea route to India?",
      "options": ["1600", "1757", "1764", "1498"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first ambassador of East India company in mughal emperor Jahangir's court?",
      "options": [
        "Thomas Roe",
        "John Hawkins",
        "William Hawkins",
        "Warren Hastings"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "At the time of independence, how many provinces were there in British India?",
      "options": ["7", "11", "14", "17"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What happened during the Chauri Chaura incident?",
      "options": [
        "A police station was set on fire",
        "Revolt by the soldiers in the British Indian armay",
        "Strike by mill workers",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which one was the first major battle fought by British East India company?",
      "options": [
        "Battle of Plassey",
        " Battle of Buxar",
        "Revolt of 1857",
        "Battle of Panipat"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following Indian freedom fighters killed a british officer in Britain?",
      "options": [
        "Bhagat Singh",
        "Chandra Shekhar Azad",
        "Udham Singh",
        "Lala Har Dayal"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}
